HERITAGE SADIQ

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Highly motivated Software Engineer - Mobile Developer. Proficient in Python, C, C++ and Dart. With experience in Django, Machine learning, Cloud Services, MLOps and Software Development; utilizing efficient communication, leadership and network skills to promote company advancements and boost overall performance. I believe I would be a valuable asset to your esteemed organization.

EXPERIENCE

Team Lead >> GADS(Andela)

Jun 2020 to Jan 2021

- Led a software development team of 13 members during the community projects to build one of the top 100 projects remotely in a fast-paced environment.
- Maintained smooth relations between team members through effective and efficient collaboration with my strong teamwork skills.
- Interfaced effectively with project team members, including mentors on slack to resolve issues, discuss ideas and collaborate with my problem solving skills.

Associate Cloud Developer >> GADS(Andela)

Jun 2020 to Jan 2021

- Learned how to use the Google Cloud Platform for various operations, including containers.
- Worked on a project and communicated with individuals from other parts of the world remotely.

Freelance Developer

Feb 2020 to Feb 2021

- Proven work experience in product development and mobile applications, ranging from Cross-platform mobile development (android, iOS), to building and deploying machine learning models to systems. See GitHub Profile
- Implementing design from Figma to build mobile applications which correspond to the UI as given and optimizing; which includes making tests, for the best user experience, with clean code.
- Conversance with the technology trends with dart and also flutter libraries. Evaluating and debugging mobile applications to optimize performance.

DevOps Intern >> VGG Internship

Jan 2020 to Jun 2020

 During the internship, I was taught about the fundamentals of Developer Operations. The internship was based on a more practical experience of DevOps.

Machine Learning Intern >> HNGInternships

Aug 2019 to Nov 2019

- During the internship, I was taught how to successfully build models out of Algorithms and successfully deploy the models to products.
- I had the opportunity of building object classification models, recommender systems, including building on the GPT-2.

Co-Lead >> Developer Student Club (Kwara State University) Oct 2019 till Present

 On campus, alongside my colleagues, we teach students in the tech community how to write code, alongside hosting events to expose them to different opportunities in different stacks.

SKILLS

RestAPILinux

- Flask
- Android
- Dart
- APIs
- Flutter
- Problem solving
- Team work
- Communication
- Leadership

- AWS
- GCP
- CI/CD
- MLOps
- Git
- JavaScript
- Python
- Machine Learning

EDUCATION

Kwara State University, Nigeria. **B.Eng** Electrical and Computer Engineering (Undergrad)

CERTIFICATIONS

- Python 3 course *Udemy*
- Flutter Advanced Course Udemy
- Deep Learning IBM
- AWS Fundamental Course Udacity
- Getting started with AWS Machine Learning Coursera
- Data Science Orientation Coursera
- Deep Learning with Tensorflow Cognitive Class(IBM)
- MTM Badge IBM
- Machine Learning Developer HNGInternships

INTERESTS

- Android
- De-Fi
- Al